<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>enterprise on Nubeblog</title>
    <link>https://nubeblog.com/tags/enterprise/</link>
    <description>Recent content in enterprise on Nubeblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>es-es</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2008 23:43:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nubeblog.com/tags/enterprise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How should Mobile projects be to survive?</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2008/04/16/how-should-mobile-projects-be-to-survive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2008 23:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2008/04/16/how-should-mobile-projects-be-to-survive/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday we discover that Mowser, the project founded by famous blogger Russell Beattie (and former colleague) was in the deadpool. Russ claimed that he ran out of money and had serious trouble with his finances.
Everyday startups are created and abandoned, but the point in this story is that he could not raise funds to continue with the project. We see almost everyday projects raising a lot of money for nothing, so why an authority in the mobile world cannot pass the first round?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flux benefits for java developers rocks: All Expense Paid Vacation for Two, Anywhere in the World</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2008/01/11/flux-benefits-for-java-developers-rocks-all-expense-paid-vacation-for-two-anywhere-in-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2008 12:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2008/01/11/flux-benefits-for-java-developers-rocks-all-expense-paid-vacation-for-two-anywhere-in-the-world/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt; &amp;lt;li&amp;gt; life insurance &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;li&amp;gt; retirement plan &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;li&amp;gt; rented car (well, higher management positions&amp;amp;#8230;) &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; Normally, these benefits are around 10% to 15% of your salary, so higher the salary (and the position) the more and better the benefits. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; I&amp;amp;#8217;m very interested in knowing what are the benefits your employers (or you if your are an employer) give to talented people to attract them. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span style=&amp;quot;font-weight: bold;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;What are your benefits at your company and where is it located?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaving AMPLIA and starting as a Freelance IT Consultant</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/10/29/leaving-amplia-and-starting-as-a-freelance-it-consultant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2007 12:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/10/29/leaving-amplia-and-starting-as-a-freelance-it-consultant/</guid>
      <description>Last years have been a wonderful time in Amplía Soluciones S.L., but nothing is forever and I think it’s time for a change. I will continue as a partner of the company but I will look for new challenges and adventures out there. You can read my public linkedin profile if you want to know a bit about my skills and experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five basic tips on preparing for a job interview</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/10/15/five-basic-tips-on-preparing-for-a-job-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2007 18:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/10/15/five-basic-tips-on-preparing-for-a-job-interview/</guid>
      <description>Last week I was talking with a friend of mine about my post Sometimes to interview developers can be funny{#i396}. We commented how most of the developers do not prepare the interview, and how they come without even visiting the website of the company. So, here goes some basic stuff you should do before attending to an interview. May be it can sound too basic, but believe me if I tell you that some developers do not care about this five topics:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rise and fall of DBAs: The tyranny of the ORM</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/09/14/rise-and-fall-of-dbas-the-tyranny-of-the-orm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2007 11:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/09/14/rise-and-fall-of-dbas-the-tyranny-of-the-orm/</guid>
      <description>There was a time when DBAs dictate how developers should use Their databases. It was early and mid-nineties and Their Word was The Truth. Those poor guys building client-server applications had to bow down before Him/Her and implement the Business Logic inside The Database Manager. Database hardware was expensive, but His/Her Highness could size the system easily because the number of clients connected was predictable. And that’s what the IT Manager wanted; predictable figures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why developers hate bug-fixing</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/09/10/why-developers-hate-bug-fixing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2007 12:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/09/10/why-developers-hate-bug-fixing/</guid>
      <description>Probably the only common thing among all developers I have worked with is the hate to bug-fixing. No matter if bugs belong to them or not. As a developer and as a manager I have quite contradictory feelings.
As a developer there was nothing more irritating than the hateful Bugzillaemails. When I was working as Technical Lead of a development team in Madrid with a QAteam in the West Coast of USA they usually started to work at our 18:00 and we usually left at 19:00 (Madrid is GMT+2 summer time).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spain will need 30000 Telecommunications Engineers in next 5 years</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/09/06/spain-will-need-30000-telecommunications-engineers-in-next-5-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2007 14:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/09/06/spain-will-need-30000-telecommunications-engineers-in-next-5-years/</guid>
      <description>The shortage of Telecommunications Engineers and Computer Engineers is becoming a serious problem for the Spanish economy. Today we can read in the news we will need to import 30000 foreign graduates for our market in the next five years. The option is obvious: bring people from India and China.
I don’t know if these politicians know anything about the IT and Telecommunications Global Market. How the hell are we going to attract foreign skilled workers?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPay: Google Patent for Mobile micropayments</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/09/03/gpay-google-patent-for-mobile-micropayments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2007 09:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/09/03/gpay-google-patent-for-mobile-micropayments/</guid>
      <description>Today in several RSS feeds I have found the same news: Google has a new patent for mobile micropayments. Micropayments using a cell phone is not new at all. I have seen some projects in Europe, specially the Spanish Mobipay. It’s a mature technology, but it’s not very successful. There are several reasons but it’s not clear why mobile micropayments are not growing. In my opinion:
 The fee is charged directly to the customer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Cell phones to drive demand for Sun servers? Who can explain this to me?</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/08/30/java-cell-phones-to-drive-demand-for-sun-servers-who-can-explain-this-to-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2007 14:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/08/30/java-cell-phones-to-drive-demand-for-sun-servers-who-can-explain-this-to-me/</guid>
      <description>Jonathan Schwartz says in SD-Asia: “…consumer cell phones on the Java software platform will drive demand for Sun servers…”. “The marketplace is going to be defined by the consuming public as much as by the traditional IT decision-maker”.Can anybody explain to me how does Sun think this is happening? How end-consumers can drive the adoption of a transparent server-side technology? End-consumer sees server side services as a commodity, they don’t care about the technology running the service if the service is good, reliable and cheap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java SOA increases and .NET declines, survey says</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/08/27/java-soa-increases-and-net-declines-survey-says/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2007 17:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/08/27/java-soa-increases-and-net-declines-survey-says/</guid>
      <description>Evans data on his semi-annual Web Services Development Survey conducted in June says that companies planning the deployment of SOAwith a Java platform has increased slightly, but the companies deploying on .NET have declinedby almost 20%. .NET is still ahead with a 31% and Java in second place with 28%. 25% will support both.
It seems the reason is the increase of the activity of the Open Source world, specially Eclipse, around SOA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sun Changes NASDAQ symbol to JAVA</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/08/23/sun-changes-nasdaq-symbol-to-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2007 22:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/08/23/sun-changes-nasdaq-symbol-to-java/</guid>
      <description>Surprise, Surprise! You can read in Jonathan Schwartz’s Weblog that they will change the NASDAQ symbol of SUN Microsystems SUNW to JAVA!!!!
The arguments are: ‘… the number of people who know Java swamps the number of people who know Sun…SUNW represents the past, and its not without a nostalgic nod that we’ve decided to look ahead…Most know Java, few know Sun…Java means limitless opportunity – for our software, systems, storage, service and microelectronics businesses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bad times for J2ME. How the iPhone with Web 2.0 apps can rule in the mobile world</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/08/22/bad-times-for-j2me-how-the-iphone-with-web-2-0-apps-can-rule-in-the-mobile-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2007 12:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/08/22/bad-times-for-j2me-how-the-iphone-with-web-2-0-apps-can-rule-in-the-mobile-world/</guid>
      <description>The day Steve Jobs said ‘Java’s not worth building in. Nobody uses Java anymore. It’s this big heavyweight ball and chain’ . Being a Java Zealot as I am, I should find easily a fist full of arguments, but may be he is right.
I have been working in the embedded and mobile world for almost four years in Amplia, and I can tell you that Java is far from being the best option for mobile and embedded development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMWare challenges Google for developers</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/08/22/vmware-challenges-google-for-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2007 10:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/08/22/vmware-challenges-google-for-developers/</guid>
      <description>Since the successful IPO of VMWare, it seems everybody is talking about them. Today we can read in Bloomberg that they are competing with Google for the best programmers. VMWare is paying $120.000-$130.000 plus stock ops to talented developers. Compared to the spanish salaries that’s really a huge amount of money. They have right now 500 open positions in Palo Alto offices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The markets lose the faith in Skype</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/08/20/the-markets-lose-the-faith-in-skype/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2007 17:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/08/20/the-markets-lose-the-faith-in-skype/</guid>
      <description>The Skype affair finally was over, but the price has been huge. While the markets are recovering from the drops of last week, eBay does not follow the trends of the markets. The image and reputation of Skype are now below zero. Just keep in mind that Skype is the one of the biggest (or the biggest) Telecommunications company in the world per number of registered users. Business and pay per use users will think twice before contracting them in the short term.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sometimes to interview developers can be funny</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/08/19/sometimes-to-interview-developers-can-be-funny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2007 23:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/08/19/sometimes-to-interview-developers-can-be-funny/</guid>
      <description>I have interviewed a lot of developers, junior and senior staff and it has become like a routine. Technical workers are nice people, rude candidates are rare. Usually their (our) self-esteem make them (us) feel they need to show they (we) are over prepared for the job. The curriculum vitae are bloated with lots of technical buzzwords that most of the people have heard of, but can’t barely talk about them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skype outage has cost more than $11000 per second to eBay</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/08/17/skype-outage-has-cost-more-than-11000-per-second-to-ebay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2007 12:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/08/17/skype-outage-has-cost-more-than-11000-per-second-to-ebay/</guid>
      <description>I have not been able to use Skypefor more than 24 hours, just like the rest of the world. It seems that the problem is serious. It has been reported that it’s an issue with a new version of the application. But it’s not so clear. Such a long outage must come from (and I’m speculating):
 A failure in the data migration from the early version of the application and a bad (or nonexistent) rollback process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 95 percent syndrome in Software Development</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/08/13/the-95-percent-syndrome-in-software-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2007 14:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/08/13/the-95-percent-syndrome-in-software-development/</guid>
      <description>Being a Project Manager, Architect, Analyst, Developer or anybody involved in the development of software, you have probably suffered the 95 percent syndrome.Imagine a software development project where things are going reasonably well: things are on schedule, Quality Assurance says things delivered are OK, the customer feel the progress, people are happy because they don’t have to work overtime and they architect and developers can apply the Best Practises. You are very close to the end of the development cycle (if you are working with an iterative and incremental methodology) and confident about the result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preezo: another Microsoft Powerpoint killer</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/08/09/preezo-another-microsoft-powerpoint-killer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2007 17:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/08/09/preezo-another-microsoft-powerpoint-killer/</guid>
      <description>Today I have discover Preezo, another web 2.0 presentations tool that looks like a killer for MicrosofPowerpoint.
The interface is mixture between Writely(sorry, Google Docs) and Microsoft Powerpoint. It’s surprisingly fast (faster than Google Docs) and you can build simple presentations very fast. If you are familiar with MS powerpointthen you can build a presentation easily.
The application allows to send by email the presentation, publish on the web and broadcast to the net and it’s also possible to embed it inside a HTML page just like any other web 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managers: if you can&amp;#8217;t code don&amp;#8217;t apply for this job</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/08/06/managers-if-you-cant-code-dont-apply-for-this-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2007 12:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/08/06/managers-if-you-cant-code-dont-apply-for-this-job/</guid>
      <description>I have read this post: ‘Architects: If you can’t code, don’t apply for senior dev jobs‘ and I can’t wait to share something happened to me not so long time ago.
I was interviewed for a position of Chief of Development in a start up. I passed two interviews with Human Resources and I only had left a face to face interview with the CEO of the company. He was(is) a very well known IT professional with an impressive technical background, but he moved to the dark side: management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The difference between an Excellent Programmer and a Natural Born Programmer</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/07/12/the-difference-between-an-excellent-programmer-and-a-natural-born-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2007 13:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/07/12/the-difference-between-an-excellent-programmer-and-a-natural-born-programmer/</guid>
      <description>Reading this blog about what he thinks a Natural Born Programmer is came to my mind a discussion about what is an excellent programmer and a natural born programmer.
The example given (detect if a number is odd or even) should be enough to differentiate between a natural born programmers and the rest.
But he is wrong.
This is the kind of solutions that people trained in Maths, Engineering or Physics can give, because they are smart people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultra Mobile Devices war is coming</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/06/07/ultra-mobile-devices-war-is-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2007 09:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/06/07/ultra-mobile-devices-war-is-coming/</guid>
      <description>Last week Palm announced a new Ultra Mobile Device (UMD) called ‘Foleo‘. This week Via has announced a new UMD reference design called Nanobook and Asus has unveiled an 3ePC, ultra low cost laptop . They are different races: Foleo is ARM-based with a limited amount of memory, Nanobook and 3ePC are x86-based. Nanobook uses VIA processors and 3ePC will use the new Tolopai Intel’s SoC. There are big differerences in memory (Foleo 256Mb, Nanobook 1Gb and 3ePC 512Mb) but not in storage and communication cababilities (all of them will have several gigs of Flash storage) and Wifi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Think twice before joining a startup</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/06/06/think-twice-before-joining-a-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2007 09:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/06/06/think-twice-before-joining-a-startup/</guid>
      <description>I recently discovered the site gobignetwork.com . It talks about how to run a startup company, how to raise funds, and more interesting information. It’s very US-centric, sometimes not valuable for a Spanish company (spain is different) like us.
I found in his blog a post that explains very well What your startup company boss wants from you. This guy sounds like the perfect mother****ing boss, but he is right 🙁</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why .NET will never be cross-platform</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/05/02/why-net-will-never-be-cross-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2007 19:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/05/02/why-net-will-never-be-cross-platform/</guid>
      <description>When I read this post asking Microsoft to make .NET cross-platform, I wondered myself why they did not use Java -the one and only trulycross-platform environment-. Apart from the the obvious, Microsoft has very good reason to avoid making .NET cross-platform:
 The jewel of the crown is Windows, so opening .NET to OS X and Linux is like shooting on your feet. As Steve Ballmersaid he loves ‘developers’… because they build ‘applications’…for the Windows OS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meraki: Mesh networks can kill Wimax</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/04/19/meraki-mesh-networks-can-kill-wimax/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2007 00:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/04/19/meraki-mesh-networks-can-kill-wimax/</guid>
      <description>One of the most interesting technologies to come are mesh networks. In Amplia we are making some prospects on these technology applied to the M2M (machine to machine) communication. Zigbeefits perfectly for small amount of data, but it’s not good when dealing with mobile communications (PDAs, laptops, MP3 players… anything interactive and portable).
The only real ubiquitousnetworks today are the mobile operators networks. GPRShas an acceptable deployment, closer to 100% of the population in developed countries, but 3G technologies are still far from being everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Google going to fire Isabel Aguilera soon?</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/04/16/is-google-going-to-fire-isabel-aguilera-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2007 16:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/04/16/is-google-going-to-fire-isabel-aguilera-soon/</guid>
      <description>Today an online Spanishnewspaper congrats Isabel Aguilera(Google Spanish CEO) for not screwing up the purchase of DoubleClickby Google. Besides the sarcasm of the headlines, the newspaper says that the time of Isabel Aguilerain Google is running out, and she could leave the company very soon.
It’s not a surprise that she will leave the company (the surprise is she has not been fired yet). Reading the profile and curricula of this women, I wonder myself if Google contracted the wrong headhunter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going live with JEE 5: Congrats SOUKI</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/04/11/going-live-with-jee-5-congrats-souki/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2007 00:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/04/11/going-live-with-jee-5-congrats-souki/</guid>
      <description>Building a project for an start-up has nothing to do with building a project for a big company: people in the start-ups normally are betting their pocket money in the project, and this means that delays, unexpected issues and bad performance of the development team have direct impact in the life of the entrepreneurs. This is the reason why I don’t want to build software for start-ups: if you have a little of empathy with them, you will carry the heavy load of their personal problems, besides of your own company troubles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Amplia&amp;#8217;s Blog about Wireless M2M</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/02/09/new-amplias-blog-about-wireless-m2m/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2007 23:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/02/09/new-amplias-blog-about-wireless-m2m/</guid>
      <description>Now that the 3GSM is going to start next week in Barcelona, we have launched our new Wireless M2M Blog. We hope to contribute with some interesting stuff regarding M2M business and services.
Rafael Morillo (our Business Development Manager) will be the main contributor to the Blog, but I hope to help him with my techie thoughts about the M2M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft mails about java and the fear to cross-platform</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/02/04/microsoft-mails-about-java-and-the-fear-to-cross-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2007 12:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/02/04/microsoft-mails-about-java-and-the-fear-to-cross-platform/</guid>
      <description>When I read the slashdot post about internal emails from Microsoft, I did not realize of the content of this email until it was posted in javalobby.
The content is scary. The mail thread comes from 1997, so after reading this emails, you can interpret the history of Java, .NET and Microsoft-Sun trial upon a several clear facts:
 Microsoft did not ever want to suport Java. Microsoft does not care about cross-platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to deal with &amp;#8216;The Toxic Engineer&amp;#8217;</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/02/02/how-to-deal-with-the-toxic-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2007 23:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/02/02/how-to-deal-with-the-toxic-engineer/</guid>
      <description>Excellent talk about how to Deal with the toxic engineer.
Things are very different here in the eastern side of the Atlantic Ocean: you cannot fire an employee because you want to, you only can fire an employee as the very last resort . Firing an employee in Spain usually is a pain in the ass for the company. The company must have things clear to take this decision.
So if you have the very bad luck to contract a Toxic Engineer for your team, may be you cannot fire him, and you have to pay him until he leaves the company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My #1 book for architects: The data model resource book vol1 and 2</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2006/12/03/my-1-book-for-architects-the-data-model-resource-book-vol1-and-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2006 23:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2006/12/03/my-1-book-for-architects-the-data-model-resource-book-vol1-and-2/</guid>
      <description>Since I started developing enterprise applications professionally (I developed video games when I was a teenager, but that’s another story…), I usually design the first version of the data models implemented in the applications developed (may be that’s the reason some people say my applications sucks…). I have worked with DBAs and Business Analysts, but it seems that the responsibility of putting in a E/R model the concepts it’s mine (well, except when I was the Technical Lead of Xpert Online in Adecco that I had the chance to recruit an excellent professional to perform this task).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>