<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jobs on Nubeblog</title>
    <link>https://nubeblog.com/tags/jobs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in jobs on Nubeblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>es-es</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2008 13:13:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nubeblog.com/tags/jobs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Again in Germany after six years</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2008/02/02/again-in-germany-after-six-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2008 13:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2008/02/02/again-in-germany-after-six-years/</guid>
      <description>This week I have visited the ESOC (The European Space Operations Centre) as part of my new job in The Server Labs. It has been a long time since I was in Germany last time, in the Due Diligence for the acquisition of JobPilot by Adecco (I was staff of Adecco). I think things have not change a lot: Germany is a good place to work if you are in technology: there are good companies, cutting edge research and development, multicultural environment, and people are really, really nice at work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flux benefits for java developers rocks: All Expense Paid Vacation for Two, Anywhere in the World</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2008/01/11/flux-benefits-for-java-developers-rocks-all-expense-paid-vacation-for-two-anywhere-in-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2008 12:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2008/01/11/flux-benefits-for-java-developers-rocks-all-expense-paid-vacation-for-two-anywhere-in-the-world/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt; &amp;lt;li&amp;gt; life insurance &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;li&amp;gt; retirement plan &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;li&amp;gt; rented car (well, higher management positions&amp;amp;#8230;) &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; Normally, these benefits are around 10% to 15% of your salary, so higher the salary (and the position) the more and better the benefits. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; I&amp;amp;#8217;m very interested in knowing what are the benefits your employers (or you if your are an employer) give to talented people to attract them. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span style=&amp;quot;font-weight: bold;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;What are your benefits at your company and where is it located?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaving AMPLIA and starting as a Freelance IT Consultant</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/10/29/leaving-amplia-and-starting-as-a-freelance-it-consultant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2007 12:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/10/29/leaving-amplia-and-starting-as-a-freelance-it-consultant/</guid>
      <description>Last years have been a wonderful time in Amplía Soluciones S.L., but nothing is forever and I think it’s time for a change. I will continue as a partner of the company but I will look for new challenges and adventures out there. You can read my public linkedin profile if you want to know a bit about my skills and experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five basic tips on preparing for a job interview</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/10/15/five-basic-tips-on-preparing-for-a-job-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2007 18:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/10/15/five-basic-tips-on-preparing-for-a-job-interview/</guid>
      <description>Last week I was talking with a friend of mine about my post Sometimes to interview developers can be funny{#i396}. We commented how most of the developers do not prepare the interview, and how they come without even visiting the website of the company. So, here goes some basic stuff you should do before attending to an interview. May be it can sound too basic, but believe me if I tell you that some developers do not care about this five topics:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linkedin looking for Grails developers</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/10/09/linkedin-looking-for-grails-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2007 10:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/10/09/linkedin-looking-for-grails-developers/</guid>
      <description>I have received information about open positions in Linkedin for Grails developers. This is very interesting because it seems that big companies have realized of the potential of Grails.
I think Linkedin is the biggest professional network site with more than 14 million users (Via wikipedia).
It sounds like a very interesting place to work, a pity I’m not in the Bay Area. 🙁</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spain vs USA comparing two Job Boards</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/09/19/spain-vs-usa-comparing-two-job-boards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2007 16:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/09/19/spain-vs-usa-comparing-two-job-boards/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago I made a search in Infojobs.es (the most popular Job Board in Spain) for open positions for Ruby On Rails developers. The result was… one! I was very surprised. Only one? With all the hype around RoR? Only one job offer?
It’s obvious that USA is more developed regarding technology than Spain, but the question is: How far are they? Can we measure the distance? Honestly I think it’s very difficult and probably comparing two countries is not the right way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>