<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>development on Nubeblog</title>
    <link>https://nubeblog.com/tags/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in development on Nubeblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>es-es</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2008 11:28:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nubeblog.com/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>First printer in a computing grid?</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2008/04/22/first-printer-in-a-computing-grid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2008 11:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2008/04/22/first-printer-in-a-computing-grid/</guid>
      <description>My friend Diego Mariño has announced in his blog that they have succesfully connected a printer to a computing grid. Think in Grid is a startup from Barcelona with an innovative Grid computing framework. They claim to be able to integrate all kind of devices in a computing grid, just like this printer:
Coming from the M2M busines I know that the Holy Grail of this business is not only the transparent connectivity of heterogenous devices through non-reliable (wireless) networks, but the capability to split and perform complex operations remotely just like if they were performed locally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The grails diaries #5: Do you need a software architect?</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2008/02/20/the-grails-diaries-5-do-you-need-a-software-architect/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2008 00:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2008/02/20/the-grails-diaries-5-do-you-need-a-software-architect/</guid>
      <description>Previous: Grails, is it really worth it?
I think there is a general misunderstanding of what kind of value can give Grails to a development shop. It seems that there are people out there that believe Grails, RoR and other breeds mean the end of Software Architectures in the web layer. The reasoning is: if the workload to develop a web application is shorter probably it means we need less skilled developers to code our applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the Google Chart API from the server side</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/12/09/using-the-google-chart-api-from-the-server-side/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2007 01:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/12/09/using-the-google-chart-api-from-the-server-side/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt; &amp;lt;li&amp;gt; commons-logging.jar &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;li&amp;gt; commons-httpclient-3.1.jar &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;li&amp;gt; commons-codec-1.3.jar &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; The piece of code to perform the HTTP request is about 20 lines. You need to pass as an argument the parameters at the right hand side of this url&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;blockquote style=&amp;quot;font-family: courier new;&amp;quot;&amp;gt; http://chart.apis.google.com/chart?&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; It returns an array of bytes with the image in PNG format. You only need to push it into the output stream of a servlet, or save it in a file like I do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ball and chain of iPhone was not Java:  it&amp;#8217;s Google Android</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/11/12/the-ball-and-chain-of-iphone-was-not-java-its-google-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2007 22:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/11/12/the-ball-and-chain-of-iphone-was-not-java-its-google-android/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes you only need to wait to understand why things happen. When Steve Jobs said ‘Java is not worth building in. Nobody uses Java anymore. It’s this big heavyweight ball and chain’, we were surprised and disappointed because like me a lot of people think that there is still room for Java in the mobile platforms. Of course we have J2ME, but we can do very few things with it. What we need is a full J2SE stack for mobiles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social bugfixing tool: Can corank.com work?</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/11/05/social-bugfixing-tool-can-corank-com-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2007 18:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/11/05/social-bugfixing-tool-can-corank-com-work/</guid>
      <description>When you start with a third party open source library or project, first thing you do is to check the its activity. If the project is dead or it’s a zombie (somebody still there just to make questions in the forums) then it’s better to start looking for a new one.
If the project is active and you decide to use it, sometimes (well, most of the times) you cannot dedicate time to give your feedback to the project.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>