<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>madness on Nubeblog</title>
    <link>https://nubeblog.com/tags/madness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in madness on Nubeblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>es-es</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2008 22:37:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nubeblog.com/tags/madness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you know what an &amp;#8216;Orakol&amp;#8217; database is?</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2008/04/07/do-you-know-what-an-orakol-database-is/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2008 22:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2008/04/07/do-you-know-what-an-orakol-database-is/</guid>
      <description>This is what I found today in ads at the top of the messages list in my GMail account:

I took me a few seconds to figure out what the hell was an ‘Orakol’ database… but when I guess it, I started laughing like crazy.
In Spain, people usually pronounce Oracle like they read it, and it’s different of the english pronounciation. If a Spaniard pronounces Oracle in english can sound snob, but writing it PHONETICALLY it’s not only snob, it’s very, very,very stupid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNA Databases: Born guilty can be true in the UK</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2008/03/18/dna-databases-born-guilty-can-be-true-in-the-uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2008 10:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2008/03/18/dna-databases-born-guilty-can-be-true-in-the-uk/</guid>
      <description>This is one of the most horrendous and unbelievable news I have read in years. It seems that some British authorities are considering the creation of DNA databases with primary school children that exhibit behaviour indicating they may become criminals in later life. So, if school can be hard for some children -specially difficult children-, can you imagine the stigmatization of being marked as ‘potential’ criminals? This is absurd!
The article is really incredible, for example: ‘…placing primary school children who have not been arrested on the database is supported by elements of criminological theory…‘ and ‘…it is possible to identify future offending traits in children as young as five…‘.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>