<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>business on Nubeblog</title>
    <link>https://nubeblog.com/tags/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in business on Nubeblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>es-es</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2008 11:28:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nubeblog.com/tags/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>First printer in a computing grid?</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2008/04/22/first-printer-in-a-computing-grid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2008 11:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2008/04/22/first-printer-in-a-computing-grid/</guid>
      <description>My friend Diego Mariño has announced in his blog that they have succesfully connected a printer to a computing grid. Think in Grid is a startup from Barcelona with an innovative Grid computing framework. They claim to be able to integrate all kind of devices in a computing grid, just like this printer:
Coming from the M2M busines I know that the Holy Grail of this business is not only the transparent connectivity of heterogenous devices through non-reliable (wireless) networks, but the capability to split and perform complex operations remotely just like if they were performed locally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How should Mobile projects be to survive?</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2008/04/16/how-should-mobile-projects-be-to-survive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2008 23:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2008/04/16/how-should-mobile-projects-be-to-survive/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday we discover that Mowser, the project founded by famous blogger Russell Beattie (and former colleague) was in the deadpool. Russ claimed that he ran out of money and had serious trouble with his finances.
Everyday startups are created and abandoned, but the point in this story is that he could not raise funds to continue with the project. We see almost everyday projects raising a lot of money for nothing, so why an authority in the mobile world cannot pass the first round?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Madrid Facebook Developer Garage was pure crap</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2008/02/19/madrid-facebook-developer-garage-was-pure-crap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2008 08:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2008/02/19/madrid-facebook-developer-garage-was-pure-crap/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I was in the event organized by Facebook in Madrid, The Madrid Facebook Developer Garage. The event was organized by FON, the Wifi company owned by Martin Varsavsky. I think Mr. Varsavsky is doing a great job trying to give visibility of the European and specially Spanish companies in Silicon Valley. The event took place in Teatro Lara, a old-fashioned theater in the heart of Madrid. A nice place, nothing to do with a garage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Again in Germany after six years</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2008/02/02/again-in-germany-after-six-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2008 13:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2008/02/02/again-in-germany-after-six-years/</guid>
      <description>This week I have visited the ESOC (The European Space Operations Centre) as part of my new job in The Server Labs. It has been a long time since I was in Germany last time, in the Due Diligence for the acquisition of JobPilot by Adecco (I was staff of Adecco). I think things have not change a lot: Germany is a good place to work if you are in technology: there are good companies, cutting edge research and development, multicultural environment, and people are really, really nice at work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Solutions affair: be evil and the blogsphere will destroy your reputation</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2008/01/11/network-solutions-affair-be-evil-and-the-blogsphere-will-destroy-your-reputation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2008 21:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2008/01/11/network-solutions-affair-be-evil-and-the-blogsphere-will-destroy-your-reputation/</guid>
      <description>Long time ago Network Solutions was the only domain registrar of .com domains, and so you had to pay them for the registration. But the monopoly ended several years ago, and discount domain registars are eating their business. They still charge $35 per year for a .com registration when you can find registrars for less than $9. Obviously they still get a lot of money from renewals, but I guess they business is not growing anymore, because they don’t want to compete with discount registrars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flux benefits for java developers rocks: All Expense Paid Vacation for Two, Anywhere in the World</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2008/01/11/flux-benefits-for-java-developers-rocks-all-expense-paid-vacation-for-two-anywhere-in-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2008 12:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2008/01/11/flux-benefits-for-java-developers-rocks-all-expense-paid-vacation-for-two-anywhere-in-the-world/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt; &amp;lt;li&amp;gt; life insurance &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;li&amp;gt; retirement plan &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;li&amp;gt; rented car (well, higher management positions&amp;amp;#8230;) &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; Normally, these benefits are around 10% to 15% of your salary, so higher the salary (and the position) the more and better the benefits. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; I&amp;amp;#8217;m very interested in knowing what are the benefits your employers (or you if your are an employer) give to talented people to attract them. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span style=&amp;quot;font-weight: bold;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;What are your benefits at your company and where is it located?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaving AMPLIA and starting as a Freelance IT Consultant</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/10/29/leaving-amplia-and-starting-as-a-freelance-it-consultant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2007 12:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/10/29/leaving-amplia-and-starting-as-a-freelance-it-consultant/</guid>
      <description>Last years have been a wonderful time in Amplía Soluciones S.L., but nothing is forever and I think it’s time for a change. I will continue as a partner of the company but I will look for new challenges and adventures out there. You can read my public linkedin profile if you want to know a bit about my skills and experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft thinks that your Facebook account costs $300</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/10/24/microsoft-thinks-that-your-facebook-account-costs-300/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2007 23:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/10/24/microsoft-thinks-that-your-facebook-account-costs-300/</guid>
      <description>Today Microsoft has acquired 1.6% of Facebook, paying 240 million dollars. So the smart guys from Redmon (and their strategic consultants, of course) think Facebook has a value of 15 billion dollars! That’s a lot of money for a company with 300 employees! But it’s not about the employees talent, it’s about the 50 million active users of the platform where the value is. And it’s really high, around 300 bucks per active user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>G2One.com: following the path of Interface21 and 37Signals for Grails</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/10/11/g2one-com-following-the-path-of-interface21-and-37signals-for-grails/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2007 09:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/10/11/g2one-com-following-the-path-of-interface21-and-37signals-for-grails/</guid>
      <description>Today I have discovered the existence of G2One.com. This is the company created by the people behind Grails. Following the business model ‘It is all about the Services, stupid!’ they have jumped into the bandwagon of companies that:
 create a framework work hard to make it first class create or find a necessity in the community offer their services as gurus to the companies  37signals is the paradigm of this approach (they created Rails).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spain will need 30000 Telecommunications Engineers in next 5 years</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/09/06/spain-will-need-30000-telecommunications-engineers-in-next-5-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2007 14:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/09/06/spain-will-need-30000-telecommunications-engineers-in-next-5-years/</guid>
      <description>The shortage of Telecommunications Engineers and Computer Engineers is becoming a serious problem for the Spanish economy. Today we can read in the news we will need to import 30000 foreign graduates for our market in the next five years. The option is obvious: bring people from India and China.
I don’t know if these politicians know anything about the IT and Telecommunications Global Market. How the hell are we going to attract foreign skilled workers?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPay: Google Patent for Mobile micropayments</title>
      <link>https://nubeblog.com/2007/09/03/gpay-google-patent-for-mobile-micropayments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2007 09:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nubeblog.com/2007/09/03/gpay-google-patent-for-mobile-micropayments/</guid>
      <description>Today in several RSS feeds I have found the same news: Google has a new patent for mobile micropayments. Micropayments using a cell phone is not new at all. I have seen some projects in Europe, specially the Spanish Mobipay. It’s a mature technology, but it’s not very successful. There are several reasons but it’s not clear why mobile micropayments are not growing. In my opinion:
 The fee is charged directly to the customer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>